<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="Kal" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Optimistic Locking in the Data Object Layer</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Optimistic Locking in the Data Object Layer</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The Data Object Layer provides a basic level of optimistic locking support using the conditional update support provided by the RDF Client API and a special version property that gets assigned to data objects. To enable optimistic locking support it is necessary to enable locking when the IDataObjectStore instance is retrieved from the context by either the OpenStore or CreateStore method (see </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Data_Object_Layer_Sample_Program" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Sample Program</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> for an example).</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">With optimistic locking enabled, the Data Object Layer checks for the presence of a special version property on every object it retrieves (the property predicate URI is http://www.brightstardb.com/.well-known/model/version). If this property is present, its value defines the current version number of the property. If the property is not present, the object is recorded as being currently unversioned. On save, the DataObjectLayer uses the current version number of all versioned data objects as the set of preconditions for the update, if any of these objects have had their version number property modified on the server, the precondition will fail and the update will not be applied. Also as part of the save, the DataObjectLayer updates the version number of all versioned data objects and creates a new version number for all unversioned data objects.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When an concurrent modification is detected, this is notified to your code by a BrightstarClientException being raised. In your code you should catch this exception and handle the error, typically either by abandoning updates (and notifying the user) or re-retrieving the modified objects and attempting the update again.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
