<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="kal_000" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Running The BrightstarDB Samples</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Running The BrightstarDB Samples</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The sample code provided with BrightstarDB varies depending on the level of package you have purchased. All samples can be found in [INSTALLDIR]\Samples. Some of the samples require editing to provide your license information before they can be successfully run - please refer to the sections below for details of what samples are included in your package and what changes you need to make to run the samples.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">BrightstarDB Mobile</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">This package provides samples for the Windows Phone 7.1 and Windows Phone 8 SDKs. These can be found in [INSTALLDIR]\Samples\WP7 and [INSTALLDIR]\Samples\WP8. To run these samples you must edit the App.xaml.cs file of each sample application and provide you licensee ID and license key where indicated.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">BrightstarDB Embedded</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">This package provides the samples from BrightstarDB Mobile plus additional samples for the different levels of API. These additional samples are found in [INSTALLDIR]\Samples\Embedded. These samples all share a single common SamplesConfiguration.cs file (which can be found in the [INSTALLDIR]\Samples\Embedded directory) which you must edit to provide your licensee ID and license key where indicated.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">BrightstarDB Server</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">This package provides the samples from BrightstarDB Mobile and BrightstarDB Embedded plus additional samples that run against a local BrightstarDB service. These samples only need editing if you want to run them against BrightstarDB running on a different machine or running on a non-default port - this is done by altering the BrightstarDB.ConnectionString property in the web.config file of the sample. These samples do not need a license key as they are BrightstarDB client applications.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
