<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<docmap>
	<doc href="Getting_Started">
		<description>An overview of BrightstarDB and quick links to getting started.</description>
	</doc>
  <doc href="Concepts">
	<description>An overview of the BrightstarDB architecture, data model and client APIs.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Why_BrightstarDB_">
    <description>Just a few of the key reasons why BrightstarDB should be your storage option of choice.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Developing_with_BrightstarDB">
    <description>A step-by-step guide to building your first BrightstarDB application.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Connection_Strings">
	<description>How to create BrightstarDB client connection strings</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Store_Persistence_Types">
	<description>BrightstarDB supports two different types of index persistence. This section explains their differences and how to choose the right one for your application.</description>
  </doc>
    <doc href="Entity_Framework">
    <description>Guide to developing with the BrightstarDB Entity Framework.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Entity_Framework_Samples">
    <description>Samples showing how to build application using the BrightstarDB Entity Framework.</description>
  </doc>
    <doc href="Data_Object_Layer">
	<description>Guide to developing with the BrightstarDB Data Object Layer API.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Dynamic_API">
    <description>Information and examples for the Dynamic API.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="RDF_Client_API">
    <description>Guide to developing with the BrightstarDB RDF Client API.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Developing_for_Windows_Phone_7">
	<description>How to use BrightstarDB in your Windows Phone apps.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="SPARQL_Endpoint">
    <description>How to configure and use the SPARQL service.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Admin_API">
	<description>How to manage BrightstarDB stores from your code.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Caching">
    <description>Explanation of the different caching options and how to enable them.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Logging">
    <description>Explanation of the different logging options.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Administration_Guide">
	<description>How to configure, backup and restore BrightstarDB databases.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="API_Documentation">
    <title>API Reference</title>
    <description>A class-by-class API reference for BrightstarDB.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Using_Polaris">
	<description>Describes Polaris, the GUI management studio for managing BrightstarDB instances.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Running_BrightstarDB">
	<description>How to configure and run BrightstarDB as an embedded database or a database server.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Licensing_Options">
    <title>BrightstarDB Licensing Options</title>
    <description>A guide to the licensing options available for using BrightstarDB.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Supported_RDF_Syntaxes">
    <description>This section describes the support in BrightstarDB for the various RDF syntaxes both for import and export.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="SdShare_Server">
    <description>Installing, configuring and developing with the SdShare Server.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Whats_New">
	<description>A list of the major changes and updates introduced in each version of BrightstarDB.</description>
  </doc>
  <doc href="Known_Issues">
    <description>A list of known issues with BrightstarDB and their workarounds.</description>
  </doc>
</docmap>